# SANDIP THAPA

Tinthana-14, Chandragiri, Bagmati Province, Nepal sandipthapa386@gmail.com (+977) 9808976977

A highly motivated and hard-working individual, graduate of Computer Science with about 2 years of active participation on web sites and application development using React.js & Next.js. Excellent communication abilities with wide range of strong technical skill-set and attention to detail. Loves to work as a Frontend Developer where I could create digital magic and elevate user interface and experience to the next level.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**JAN 2022 - PRESENT** 

#### JR. FRONTEND DEVELOPER, CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

- Convert Figma designs into web pages using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Develop new user-facing features using React.js and Next.js with Typescript.
- Develop and maintain fast, bug-free, and re-usable components for the in-house product.
- Collaborate with back-end team to understand and contribute in developing system architecture and database schema.
- Collaborate with design team to enhance user interfaces and its experience.
- Implement and manage version controlling of the project using git flow.
- Implement Docker for easier system deployments.

**SEPT 2021 - DEC 2021** 

## FRONTEND DEVELOPER - INTERNSHIP, EKBANA SOLUTIONS PTE. LTD.

- Developed supermarket app with React.js.
- API integration and data handling using Context API.
- Got to learn about Software Development Life Cycle using SCRUM.

#### **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2021

## BSc (Hons) IT, HERALD COLLEGE, UNIVERSITY OF WOLVERHAMPTON

- Introduced to fundamentals of programming.
- Introduced to Data Structure and Algorithms.
- Introduced to Database Management Systems.
- Assigned to multiple mini and group projects.
- Worked on different research, communication and collaboration skills.

2016 - 2018

### INTERMEDIATE - SCIENCE, KATHMANDU BERNHARDT COLLEGE

• Majors: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS
- Javascript
- TypeScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- React Query

- Bootstrap 5
- Mantine UI
- Formik
- Yup
- Git
- Gitlab
- DockerFigma

- Communication
- Team Work
- Critical Thinking
- Leadership

## **SOCIAL ACCOUNTS**

- Portfolio: <a href="https://www.sandipthapa.com.np/">https://www.sandipthapa.com.np/</a>
- LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandipthapa99/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandipthapa99/</a>
- **Github:** <a href="https://github.com/sandipthapa99/">https://github.com/sandipthapa99/</a>